<sect1 id="perf">
	<title>mnoGoSearch performance issues
<indexterm><primary>Performance issues</primary></indexterm>
</title>
	<sect2 id="perf-mysql">
		<title>MySQL performance</title>
		<para>MySQL users may declare mnoGoSearch tables with the
<option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE=1</option> option. This will make the updating
of indexes faster, as these are not logged to disk until the file is
closed. <option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE</option> excludes updating indexes on
disk completely. </para>
		<para>With it, indexes are processed only in memory and
written onto disk as a last resort, by the <command>FLUSH TABLES
</command> command or at mysqld shutdown. This can take even minutes and
impatient user can <literal>kill -9 mysql server</literal> and break
index files with this. Another downside is that you should run
<literal>myisamchk</literal> on these tables before you start mysqld
to ensure that they are okay if something killed mysqld in the
middle.</para>
		<para>Because of it, we didn't include this table
option into the default tables structure. However, as the key information
can always be generated from the data, you should not lose anything by
using <option>DELAY_KEY_WRITE</option>. So, use this option at your
own risk.</para>
	</sect2>
	<sect2 id="perf-optimization">
		<title>Post-indexing optimization</title>
		<para>This article was supplied by Randy Winch <email>gumby@cafes.net</email>
		</para>
		<para>I have some performance numbers that some of you
might find interesting. I'm using RH 6.2 with the 2.2.14-6.1.1 kernel
update (allows files larger than 2 gig) and mysql 2.23.18-alpha.  I
have just indexed most of our site using mnoGoSearch 3.0.18:
		<programlisting>

          mnoGoSearch statistics

    Status    Expired      Total
   -----------------------------
       200     821178    2052579 OK
       301        797      29891 Moved Permanently
       302          3          3 Moved Temporarily
       304          0          7 Not Modified
       400          0         99 Bad Request
       403          0          7 Forbidden
       404      30690     100115 Not found
       500          0          1 Internal Server Error
       503          0          1 Service Unavailable
   -----------------------------
     Total     852668    2182703

</programlisting>
</para>

		<para>I optimize the data by dumping it into a file
using <option>SELECT * INTO OUTFILE</option>, sort it using the system
sort routine into word (CRC) order and then reloading it into the
database using the procedure described in the 
<ulink url="http://www.mysql.com/documentation/mysql/commented/manual.php?section=Insert_speed">mysql online manual</ulink>.</para>
		<para>The performance is wonderful. My favorite test
is searching for "John Smith". The optimized database version takes
about 13 seconds. The raw version takes about 73 seconds.</para>

		<programlisting>
Search results: john : 620241 smith : 177096
Displaying documents 1-20 of total 128656 found
</programlisting>
		<para>You may also take <ulink
					       url="http://mnogosearch.org/download.html">optimize.sh</ulink> script from our site. It was written by Joe Frost <email>joe_frost@omnis-software.com</email> and implements Randy's idea.</para>
	</sect2>
</sect1>
