<sect1 id="categories">
  <title>Categories
    <indexterm><primary>Categories</primary></indexterm>
  </title>
  <para>
   Starting from version 3.1.1 &mnogo;
   supports nested categories.
  </para>
  <para>There is a category editor written in
  <application>PHP3</application> and <application>Perl</application>.
   You can get it from
   <ulink url="http://mnogosearch.org/download.html">
   &mnogo; downloads page</ulink>.
  </para>
  <para>
    Categories are similar to the tags, but nested.
    So you can have one category inside another and so on.
  </para>
  <para>Basic points:
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>there are up to 6 nested levels;</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>every level occupies two hexadecimal or 36-base digits;</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>the parameter for setting category is a
        <parameter>path</parameter>, which can be empty
        (which means the root category) or up to 10 chars
        long (in case of the deepest category).
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  <para>You can also set up <emphasis>symlinks</emphasis>, i.e.
  categories that are actually links to other categories.
  This is the role of the <literal>link</literal> database
  field. In the symlink, the last two characters should be
  @@. In example above Moto-&gt;BMW is a link to Auto-&gt;BMW.</para>

  <para>First notice that a category in the server table is set to be
  11 characters long. This means you can use a valid character to keep
  track of the categories. If you are going to keep a category tree of any
  size, then I would suggest using the category editor from 
  <ulink url="http://mnogosearch.org/download.html">
  &mnogo; downloads page</ulink>.
  </para>
  
  <para>You can use either the tag column or the category column
on the server to do the same thing. Or you can categorize a site in two
different ways. For example you could keep track of sites that are
owned by a certain company and then categorize them as well. You could
use the tag option to keep a trace of ownership and use the category option
for categories. When I explain the category option, note it goes the same
for the tag option.
  </para>

  <para>A category can be broken down any way you choose. But
for it to work with the category editor, I believe for now, you have
to use two characters for each level. If you use the category editor
you have the choice to use a hex number going from 0-F or a 36 base
number going from 0-Z. Therefore a top-level category like 'Auto'
would be 01. If it has a subcategory like 'Ford', then it would be 01
(the parent category) and then 'Ford' which we will give 01. Put those
together and you get 0101. If 'Auto' had another subcategory named
'VW', then its id would not be 01 because it belongs to the 'Ford'
category but 02 because it's the next category. So its id would
be 0102. If VW had a sub category called 'Engine' then it's id would
start at 01 again and it would get the 'VW' id 02 and 'Auto' id of 01,
making it 010201.</para>

  <para>If you want to search for sites under that category then
you could pass it <literal>cat=010201</literal> into the url...so
you could create a select box that would look like that:
  <programlisting>
&lt;OPTION value="01"&gt;AUTO
&lt;OPTION value="0101"&gt;Ford
</programlisting>
  </para>
  <para>and so on...</para>
</sect1>
